Overview

Language agnostic software engineer with a love for both object-oriented programming and functional programming. A self-motivated problem-solver that delivers business value as an individual contributor and brings out the best in others as a team lead.

- Focuses on meeting the needs of the users and the business.
- Follows agile methodologies to consistently deliver working software.
- Strives to write code that is simple and maintainable by other engineers.
- Combines skills, experience, and creativity to provide solutions to complex problems.
- Searches for leadership opportunities to encourage personal and organizational growth.

Tools

Current - OOP, Design Patterns, SOLID, DDD, Agile, Scrum, .NET, C#, HTML, JavaScript, CSS, SQL, Visual Studio, ReSharper/Rider, Visual Studio Code, Vim, Unit Testing, TDD, Git, GitHub, Azure DevOps, Azure, Terraform, PowerShell

Previous - C++, Java, RTOS, 2D/3D Graphics, Linux, Multi-threading, Networking Interests - FP, F#, TypeScript

Experience

Qualtrax (Acquired by Ideagen, March 2021) Senior Software Engineer, January 2018 - Present

Served as the leader for a development team of product engineers to maintain legacy QMS software. Daily activities included development, pairing, mentoring, reviewing code, and facilitating regular agile ceremonies focused on continuous improvement of the team.

- Conducted research and refactoring for a new multi-tenant architecture that reduced hosting costs by enabling the application to use shared resources in Azure.
- Integrated SAML SSO component into the application which enabled customers to use their own identity providers for a seamless login experience.
- Regularly facilitated book clubs and community activities to strengthen shared engineering principles and share new patterns and practices across vertical teams.

InventureIT

Senior Software Engineer, January 2016 - January 2018

Collaborated with other developers on an agile team to enhance and expand company's software portfolio for clients in various industries.

- Architected reusable, multi-tenant web application using ASP.NET MVC and Entity
 Framework to enable teachers to track student interventions and learning progress.
- Streamlined workflow of practice management software to increase efficiency in physician offices, decrease errors in data entry, and improve patient experience.
- Mentored other team members to improve software development and release processes and increase overall development efficiency.

Shaw Industries, Inc.

Senior Software Engineer, January 2013 - January 2016 Systems Engineer, December 2007 - January 2013

Worked with other developers in agile teams to improve and expand the company's existing library of manufacturing applications.

- Led software architecture of several projects including a custom service bus, an efficiency and production tracking system, and a proprietary manufacturing process.
- Researched and evaluated new technologies for use in application development and led several presentations to encourage technical growth within the group.
- Coordinated efforts with external groups to integrate shop floor systems into HMI and order management applications on the manufacturing floor.

Education and Certifications

Duke University, BS Computer Science, 1999; Microsoft, MCSD, 2020

Volunteerism and Hobbies

Scenic City Summit, Organizer, 2017-2019; TEALS, Volunteer Teacher, 2020

Hobbies include reading (mostly personal/professional development), conferences and user groups, coding for fun, computer and table-top gaming, Netflix binge-watching, cat wrangling, and beer brewing.

References, code samples, and extended work history available upon request.